Guide to the Diane Ackerman papers, 1971-1997.
Ackerman, Diane papers,
- Series I. Published Books
  - Monk Seal Hideaway, New York, Crown, 1995
    - Manuscript - Original manuscript, ts. with handwritten corrections, 16 pages, letter from Crown books, Jan. 23, 1997 (Box 6, Folder 11)
    - Galleys - (int. mechs), July 25, 1994: pp. 1-17 and cover (Box 10, Folder 2)
  - The Rarest of the Rare, New York, Random House, 1995
    - Correspondence from DA's editor to DA, Jan.-Feb., Apr. 1995; partial manuscript: notes on pp. 76-98, 111, 162-193 (Box 6, Folder 12)
    - Partial manuscript: notes on pp. 163-187, 193-205, 207-254 (Box 6, Folder 13)
    - Typesetting manuscript - Computer printout, March 27, 1995: 8 preliminary pages, pp. 1-38 (Box 6, Folder 14)
    - Typesetting manuscript - Computer printout, March 27, 1995: pp. 39-110 (Box 6, Folder 15)
    - Typesetting manuscript - Computer printout, March 27, 1995: pp. 111-183 (Box 6, Folder 16)
    - Typesetting manuscript - Computer printout, March 27, 1995: pp. 184-254, "about the author," "about the type" (Box 6, Folder 17)
    - Index - Typesetting copy, computer printout, 40 pages, Aug. 3, 1995; 5" floppy disk; page proofs: pp. 177-186; blues, pp. 175-184 (Box 6, Folder 18)
    - Laser proof - Note from publisher, 3 loose pages, 22 preliminary pages, proof, Sept. 20, 1995: pp. 1-28 (Box 6, Folder 19)
    - Laser proof - Sept. 20, 1995: pp. 29-83 (Box 6, Folder 20)
    - Laser proof - Sept. 20, 1995: pp. 84-135 (Box 6, Folder 21)
    - Laser proof - Sept. 20, 1995: pp. 136-184 (Box 6, Folder 22)
    - Layout of book jacket (Box 10, Folder 3)
  - A Slender Thread, New York, Random House, 1996
    - Typesetting manuscript - Computer printout: 8 preliminary pages, pp. 3-65 (Box 6, Folder 23)
    - Typesetting manuscript - Computer printout: pp. 66-132 (Box 6, Folder 24)
    - Typesetting manuscript - Computer printout: pp. 133-209 (Box 6, Folder 25)
    - Typesetting manuscript - Computer printout: 210-289 (Box 6, Folder 26)
    - Typesetting manuscript - Computer printout: 290-361, "about the author," "about the type" (Box 6, Folder 27)
    - Galleys - master, 1st pass, photocopy, July 16, 1996: 11 preliminary pages, pp. 1-63 (Box 6, Folder 28)
    - Galleys - master, 1st pass, photocopy, July 16, 1996: pp. 64-142 (Box 6, Folder 29)
    - Galleys - master, 1st pass, photocopy, July 16, 1996: pp. 143-215 (Box 6, Folder 30)
    - Galleys - master, 1st pass, photocopy, July 16, 1996: pp. 216-296, "about the author," "about the type" (Box 6, Folder 31)
    - Galleys - master, 2nd pass, photocopy, Sept. 4, 1996: 11 preliminary pages, pp. 1-63 (Box 7, Folder 1)
    - Galleys - master, 2nd pass, photocopy, Sept. 4, 1996: pp. 64-134 (Box 7, Folder 2)
    - Galleys - master, 2nd pass, photocopy, Sept. 4, 1996: pp. 135-229 (Box 7, Folder 3)
    - Galleys - master, 2nd pass, photocopy, Sept. 4, 1996: pp. 230-296, "about the author," "about the type" (Box 7, Folder 4)
    - Galleys - Sept. 19, 1996: 10 preliminary pages, pp. 1-62 (Box 7, Folder 5)
    - Galleys - Sept. 19, 1996: pp. 63-134 (Box 7, Folder 6)
    - Galleys - Sept. 19, 1996: pp. 135-229 (Box 7, Folder 7)
    - Galleys - Sept. 19, 1996: pp. 230-296, "about the type" (Box 7, Folder 8)
    - Galleys - Sept. 19, 1996: 9 preliminary pages, pp. 1-61 (Box 7, Folder 9)
    - Galleys - Sept. 19, 1996: pp. 62-134 (Box 7, Folder 10)
    - Galleys - Sept. 19, 1996: pp. 135-229 (Box 7, Folder 11)
    - Galleys - Sept. 19, 1996: pp. 230-296, "about this type" (Box 7, Folder 12)
    - Index - Typesetting copy, computer printout with copy editor's notes, 29 pages; page proof revisions, fax copy, pp. 297-299, 302, November 4, 1996 (Box 7, Folder 13)
    - Blues - Nov. 20, 1996, pp. 1-150 (Box 7, Folder 14)
    - Blues - Nov. 20, 1996, pp. 151-310 (Box 7, Folder 15)
    - Miscellaneous handwritten notes, first drafts, etc. (Box 7, Folder 16-17)
    - Author's galleys - July 16, 1996, corrections: pp. i-x, 1-68 (Box 7, Folder 18)
    - Author's galleys - July 16, 1996, corrections: pp. 69-145 (Box 7, Folder 19)
    - Author's galleys - July 16, 1996, corrections: pp. 146-221 (Box 7, Folder 20)
    - Author's galleys - July 16, 1996, corrections: pp. 222-296, 2 "about the author," "about the type (Box 7, Folder 21)
    - Author's galleys - Sept. 4, 1996, author's 2nd pass corrections: pp. i-x, 1-68 (Box 7, Folder 22)
    - Author's galleys - Sept. 4, 1996, author's 2nd pass corrections: pp. 69-145 (Box 7, Folder 23)
    - Author's galleys - Sept. 4, 1996, author's 2nd pass corrections: pp. 146-221 (Box 7, Folder 24)
    - Author's galleys - Sept. 4, 1996, author's 2nd pass corrections: pp. 222-296, "about the author," "about the type" (Box 7, Folder 25)
    - Photograph of design, 11" x 14" black and white print (Box 10, Folder 4)
  - Bats: Shadows in the Night, New York, Crown, June 1997
    - Galleys - Feb. 27, 1997: pp. 1-15; 3 early book jackets (Box 10, Folder 5)
    - Stand-up display poster (Folder O/S)
  - I Praise My Destroyer, New York, Random House, 1997
    - Proof - Typesetting copy, October 28, 1997, title page-p.27 (Box 11, Folder 1)
    - Proof - Typesetting copy, October 28, 1997, pp. 28-81, 70, 79, 86, 109 (Box 11, Folder 2)
    - Proof - Master set second pass; December 12, 1997, 10:31 A.M.; title page-p. 52 (Box 11, Folder 3)
    - Proof - Master set second pass; December 12, 1997, 10:31 A.M.; pp. 53-118 (Box 11, Folder 4)
    - Proof - Master set first pass; December 12, 1997, 3:23 P.M.; title page-p. 47 (Box 11, Folder 5)
    - Proof - Master set first pass; December 12, 1997, 3:23 P.M.; pp. 48-118 (Box 11, Folder 6)
- Series II. Published Articles
  - "Bats," New Yorker, Feb. 29, 1988
    - Partial manuscript: handwritten, 12 pages; partial manuscript: ts. with handwritten corrections, 6 pages; partial manuscript: computer printout with handwritten corrections, 24 pages (Box 7, Folder 26)
    - Manuscript - Computer printout with handwritten corrections, Sept. 26, 1987: 84 pages (Box 7, Folder 27)
    - Manuscript - Computer printout with handwritten corrections, Sept. 26, 1987: 83 pages (Box 7, Folder 28)
    - Galleys - photocopy, Nov. 2, 1987: 48 pages (Box 7, Folder 29)
    - Galleys - photocopy, Feb. 2, 1988: 45 pages (Box 7, Folder 30)
    - Galleys - photocopy, Feb. 2, 1988: 48 pages (Box 7, Folder 31)
    - Proofs - Page proofs, photocopy, Feb. 29, 1988: 45 pages (pp. 3-47) (Box 7, Folder 32)
    - Publication - New Yorker, Feb. 29, 1988 (Box 7, Folder 33)
    - Galleys - photocopy, Feb. 2, 1988: 45 pages (Box 10, Folder 6)
  - "Crocodilians," New Yorker, Oct. 10, 1988
    - Manuscript - Computer printout with handwritten corrections, March 27, 1988: 60 pages (Box 7, Folder 34)
    - Notes, 4 pages handwritten; computer printout, 26 pages (Box 7, Folder 35)
    - Galleys - photocopy, May 17, 1988: 47 pages (Box 7, Folder 36)
    - Galleys - photocopy, May 17, 1988: 47 pages (Box 7, Folder 37)
    - Page proofs - photocopy, not illustrated, Oct. 10, 1988: 45 pages (pp. 3-48) (Box 7, Folder 38)
    - Page proofs - photocopy, illustrated, Oct. 10, 1988: 35 pages (pp. 42-76) (Box 7, Folder 39)
    - Background material - Kent Vliet, computer printout of interview (Tape One): 39 pages (Box 8, Folder 1)
    - Background material - Kent Vliet, computer printouts of interview (Tape Two): 41 pages (2 copies) (Box 8, Folder 2)
    - Background materials - Peter Brazaitis, computer printout of interview: 9 pages; Arthur Jones, computer printout of interview (Tape Four): 15 pages; George Campbell, computer printout of interview (Tape Three): 31 pages (Box 8, Folder 3)
    - Publication - New Yorker, Oct. 10, 1988 (Box 8, Folder 4)
    - Galleys - 1st revision, photocopy, Sept. 8, 1988: 47 pages (Box 10, Folder 7)
  - "Penguins," New Yorker, July 10, 1989
    - Draft - Final draft, computer printout, March 14, 1989: 78 pages (Box 8, Folder 5)
    - Draft - New Yorker draft, computer printout: 78 pages (Box 8, Folder 6)
    - Galleys - 1st galley, photocopy, March 14, 1989: 53 pages (Box 8, Folder 7)
    - Page proof - photocopy, July 10, 1989: 51 pages (pp. 3-54) (Box 8, Folder 8)
    - Publication - New Yorker, July 10, 1989 (Box 8, Folder 9)
    - Galleys - 1st galley, photocopy, March 14, 1989: 53 pages (Box 10, Folder 8)
    - Galleys - photocopy, July 10, 1989: 53 pages (pp. 2-54) (Box 10, Folder 9)
    - Galleys - Reader's galleys, photocopy, July 10, 1989: 53 pages (pp. 2-54) (Box 10, Folder 10)
  - "Whales," New Yorker, Feb. 26, 1990
    - Handwritten notes: 3 pages; computer printout with handwritten corrections: 88 pages (Box 8, Folder 10)
    - Manuscript - Computer printout with handwritten corrections, 68 pages (Box 8, Folder 11)
    - New Yorker draft, Nov. 14, 1989: 50 pages; 15 page insert, 2 pages notes (Box 8, Folder 12)
    - Galley - 1st galley, photocopy, Jan. 4, 1990: 54 pages; 2 miscellaneous pages (Box 8, Folder 13)
    - Page proofs, photocopy, Feb. 26, 1990: 50 pages (pp. 3-53) (Box 8, Folder 14)
    - Publication - New Yorker, Feb. 26, 1990 (Box 8, Folder 15)
    - Notebooks: 2 - 6" x 4" spiral notebooks - 35 sheets each; 1 - 8" x 10 1/2" spiral notebook - 70 sheets (Box 8, Folder 16)
    - Page proofs - photocopy, Feb. 26, 1990: 50 pages (pp. 3-53) (Box 10, Folder 11)
  - "Albatrosses," New Yorker, Sept. 24, 1990
    - Handwritten notes, 5 pages; draft, computer printout with handwritten corrections, 9 pages; computer printout with handwritten corrections, 75 pages (Box 8, Folder 17)
    - Manuscript - Computer printout with handwritten correction, 77 pages (Box 8, Folder 18)
    - Manuscript - Computer printout with handwritten corrections, photocopy, April 25, 1990: 54 pages (Box 8, Folder 19)
    - Galley - photocopy, April 25, 1990: 45 pages (Box 8, Folder 20)
    - Galley - photocopy, Aug. 21, 1990: 45 pages (Box 8, Folder 21)
    - Page proofs - photocopy, Sept. 24, 1990: 45 pages (Box 8, Folder 22)
    - Background material - Peter Harrison, computer printout transcript of interview, Tori-shama, Japan, 1989: Tape 1, 30 pages; Tape 1, 52 pages (Box 8, Folder 23)
    - Background materials - Peter Harrison, computer printout transcript of interview, Tori-shama, Japan, 1989: Tapes 2 and 3, 52 pages; computer printout transcript of lecture given by Peter Harrison: "Ocean Nomads. Albatrosses," 27 pages (Box 8, Folder 24)
    - Publication - New Yorker, Sept. 24, 1990 (Box 8, Folder 25)
    - Notebooks - 2 - 6" x 4" spiral notebooks - 35 sheets (Box 8, Folder 26)
  - "Golden Monkeys," New Yorker, June 24, 1991
    - Galley - 1st revision, photocopy, May 1, 1991: 35 pages (Box 8, Folder 27)
    - Galley - fax copy, June 24, 1991: 35 pages (pp. 3-37) (Box 8, Folder 28)
    - Notebooks - 2 - 6" x 4" spiral notebooks; 1 - 7" x 4 1/2" flat notebook (Box 8, Folder 29)
  - "Insect Love," New Yorker, Aug. 17, 1992
    - Manuscript - Computer printout with handwritten corrections: 57 pages (Box 8, Folder 30)
    - Galley - photocopy, April 20, 1992: 36 pages (Box 8, Folder 31)
    - Page proofs - photocopy, July 30, 1992: 35 pages (pp. 3-37) (Box 8, Folder 32)
    - Galley - fax copy, Aug. 5, 1992: 16 pages (Box 8, Folder 33)
  - "Rodney Marsh" (publication unknown)
    - Profile of Rodney Marsh, soccer player, computer printout, July 11, 1980: 26 pages (Box 8, Folder 34)
  - "Last Refuge of the Monk Seals," National Geographic
    - Manuscript (earlier titles: "Hawaiian Monk Seals" and "Saving Hawaiian Monk Seals") - Computer printout, edited: 39 pages; text copy: 27 pages (Box 8, Folder 35)
    - Page proofs - photocopy, Oct. 11, 1991: 14 pages, 3 extra pages; page proofs, printer's set, fax copy, Nov. 27, 1991: 14 pages (Box 8, Folder 36)
    - Page proofs - photocopy, Nov. 11, 1991 (Danielle): 14 pages; page proofs, photocopy, Nov. 27, 1991: 18 pages (Box 8, Folder 37)
    - Galley - illustrated, with handwritten corrections, Aug. 22, 1991: 13 pages (Box 8, Folder 38)
    - Miscellaneous - National Geographic Society Expense Account book; sample page from galley; dummy, fax, 09/10/91: 7 pages; computer printout: 26 pages (Box 8, Folder 39)
    - Notebooks - 2 - 6" x 4" spiral notebooks (Box 8, Folder 40)
  - "In Praise of Squirrels," National Geographic, Nov. 1995
    - Proofs - Fitted first proof, with handwritten corrections, July 10, 1995: pp. 98-113; note from publisher; final for release, with handwritten corrections, July 21, 1995: pp. 98-113 (Box 8, Folder 41)
    - Galley, manuscript - Fax, Aug. 4, 1995: pp. 98-113; 2 manuscript text copies: 19 pages each (Box 8, Folder 42)
  - "The Natural History of a Leaf," Condé Nast's Traveler, May 1988
    - Manuscript - Computer printout with handwritten corrections, 7 pages (Box 8, Folder 43)
  - Essay: "How to Watch the Sky," Parade Magazine, Feb. 18, 1990
    - Manuscript - Computer printout with handwritten corrections, Dec. 5, 1988: 16 pages; computer printout with handwritten corrections, Jan. 12, 1989: 18 pages; page proofs, July 30, 1991: 8 pages (Box 8, Folder 44)
  - Essay: "Where the Sun Dines" (Amazon Rain Forest), Travel-Holiday, March 1990
    - Manuscript - Computer printout with handwritten corrections: 26 pages; computer printout with handwritten corrections: 23 pages (Box 8, Folder 45)
  - "The Children of Interplast," New York Times Magazine, Oct. 20, 1991
    - Article - Computer printout with handwritten corrections, Nov. 8, 1989: 57 pages; notes, computer printout: pp. 14-48 (Box 9, Folder 1)
    - Notebooks - 1 - 6" x 4" spiral notebook - 35 sheets; 1 - 7 3/4" x 5" spiral notebook - 80 sheets; 1 - 9 1/2" x 6" spiral notebook - 80 sheets (Box 9, Folder 2)
- Series III. Unpublished Manuscripts
  - "Senses of Animals"
    - Handwritten drafts, printout of early draft (untitled poetry book for children to be published by Crown, 1998 (Box 8, Folder 46)
  - Novel: "Sympathetic Magic"
    - Manuscript - Incomplete computer printout with handwritten corrections: pp. 1-76 (Box 9, Folder 3)
    - Manuscript - Incomplete computer printout with handwritten corrections: pp. 83-158 (Box 9, Folder 4)
    - Manuscript - Incomplete computer printout with handwritten corrections: pp. 159-224 (Box 9, Folder 5)
- Series IV. Publicity
  - Publicity photos, 1971-1997 (Box 9, Folder 12)
  - Poster - "A Luminous Evening With Diane Ackerman" (Folder O/S)
- Series V. Reseach Materials
  - Miscellany - Maps, newspaper and magazine clippings, travel information, and travel-related correspondence (Box 9, Folder 6-9)
  - Audio cassette - "Diomedea albatrus," Library of Natural Sounds (Box 9, Folder 10)
- Series VI. Personal
  - Photocopies of incoming letters from May Swenson, 1973-1985; memorial tribute to May Swenson, Mar. 28, 1991 (Box 9, Folder 11)
  - Printed matter - Poster from March 22-25, 1983 writers' festival; The New Yorker Voices, 1990; article in Victoria magazine, January 1997 (Box 9, Folder 13)
  - 2 press badges for Parade magazine (Box 9, Folder 14)